<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Naomi's Blog RSS Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[This blog contains Naomi's random ramblings and thoughts.]]></description><link>https://blog.nhcarrigan.com</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 19:07:01 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Insomnia, Client Work, and a Never-Ending Week]]></title><description><![CDATA[I found this week to be quite a struggle. While I’ve managed to keep moving forward, I have definitely been much lower in energy than I…]]></description><link>https://blog.nhcarrigan.com/2022/April/2022-04-23/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.nhcarrigan.com/2022/April/2022-04-23/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I found this week to be quite a struggle. While I’ve managed to keep moving forward, I have definitely been much lower in energy than I normally am. This has resulted in falling behind on some work, though not enough to be terribly concerning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Insomnia&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest struggle this week was that my insomnia decided to hit me in full force. One might think that more waking hours means more time to work, but in reality it’s absolutely brutal on my productivity. Having to shake the “cobwebs” from my head throughout the day definitely puts a damper on my ability to think about the code I am trying to write. I was thankfully able to get some rest last night, and I am hoping to get everything back on track this weekend, but there is definitely some catching up to be done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Issue Tracker&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last thing I want to do is disappoint my clients, so with the week being somewhat rough the first thing to go on the back burner was my personal projects. I’ve done my best, at the very least, to ensure issues and feature ideas are logged on GitHub, though I’m sure some have slipped through the cracks. However, one pattern I’ve noticed is many people join my community server and ask “How can I contribute?“. I like to think my contributing documentation is quite in-depth, but I believe that having my projects spread across a few GitHub organisations is creating an obstacle for new contributors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To alleviate this, I slapped together a quick &lt;a href=&quot;https://contribute.nhcarrigan.com&quot;&gt;Issue Finder&lt;/a&gt; website. The idea here was to allow new contributors to see all of the open issues across my organisations, and filter by organisation and by key labels (&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;good first issue&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;help wanted&lt;/code&gt;). These key features are (I believe) entirely functional, but the design needs some additional work. My goal was to ship an MVP for this quickly to address the contribution obstacle, which might take some of the pressure off myself for these personal projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Feedhive&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mentioned last week that I was selected for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/eddiehubcommunity&quot;&gt;EddieHub&lt;/a&gt; Ambassador Programme. One of the perks of that is access to a “Brand”-level account on &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedhive.io/&quot;&gt;FeedHive&lt;/a&gt;, which I have started exploring a bit this week. I’m hoping that the targeted analytics will help me better time my product posts, and being able to manage my multiple accounts is incredibly helpful. I’m sure I will have more to share on this as I settle in to using it and incorporate it more into my workflow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Client and Personal Work&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of my above struggles, I’ve still ended up falling behind on one of my paid projects. I’m hoping to spend this weekend getting caught up and back on track, though unfortunately this is going to set me back a bit on my game development work. I’m pretty much at my limit for the amount of work I can take on - barring unforeseen circumstances (like insomnia), I’m right at the level of manageable but not overwhelming. Now it’s a matter of getting the balance and time management sorted out so I can maximise my productivity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll still continue working on my personal projects, and my ultimate goal is to get my &lt;a href=&quot;https://nhcarrigan.itch.io&quot;&gt;game series&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://donate.nhcarrigan.com&quot;&gt;sponsorships&lt;/a&gt; to become stronger revenue streams so I can spend some time on the community aspects as well. If you haven’t already, you should definitely join our &lt;a href=&quot;https://chat.nhcarrigan.com&quot;&gt;Discord server&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Community Updates&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of community stuff… Our server continues to grow slowly but steadily, and we are nearing the 500 member mark. Looking at the metrics, about 430 of these members have been active in the community within the last month. I could probably push for more rapid growth, but I’d much rather have slower growth that results in more long-term engagement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started writing this post this morning while on a Twitter Space (about content creation, funnily enough), which I greatly enjoyed. I still find myself tempted to host my own Twitter Space, to take the next step from speaking on others’ spaces. But I am still struggling to find a good topic to start with - something that I can speak on, but that people would also want to hear about. If you have anything you’d like to hear about, let me know!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In closing, I’d like to mention that I know this post touches on some personal stuff. Honestly, that’s likely going to be the case for many of these posts. As we find success, it is easy to get sucked in to only posting about our wins. In my opinion, it’s equally beneficial for people to see that I am human too, and that I encounter struggles and setbacks just like they do. Developers, especially those starting out, seem to frequently compare their path to someone else’s - if we aren’t real about our journey and the challenges we face, it can be very discouraging to someone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully you enjoyed the read, and we’ll see you next week!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Broken Dev Environment]]></title><description><![CDATA[Okay, my first actual post. Here goes nothing… This week was, honestly, a bit of a whirlwind. WSL Issues Monday morning I booted up my…]]></description><link>https://blog.nhcarrigan.com/2022/April/2022-04-16/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.nhcarrigan.com/2022/April/2022-04-16/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Okay, my first actual post. Here goes nothing… This week was, honestly, a bit of a whirlwind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;WSL Issues&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monday morning I booted up my computer, made my coffee, and sat down to start my workday. Open Microsoft Terminal to launch my WSL environment, and run in to a “cannot find that exe” error. Oh no.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some solid Google-fu later and I discover the solution is to unmount the installed distro, download the update, and use the new image. Which worked - I was back in WSL and ready to code! Unfortunately, my files weren’t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m assuming it was the unmounting process, but somewhere along the way I lost all of the files within the WSL partition. All my installed software, my cloned repos, &lt;strong&gt;everything&lt;/strong&gt;. I was able to get things back up and running, but that involved reinstalling all of my tooling and reconfiguring all of my local &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;.env&lt;/code&gt; files for my projects. It took some time, even with only focusing on the main projects I actively work on. Thankfully I have somewhat &lt;a href=&quot;https://nhcarrigan.com/notes&quot;&gt;extensive notes&lt;/a&gt; for setting up a new environment. Big thank you to past me, who documented all of that for the time I choose to upgrade my machine (not anticipating something like this).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Game Dev&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A friend of mine started a game jam in her server, so I decided to &lt;a href=&quot;https://nhcarrigan.itch.io/ruus-goblin-quest&quot;&gt;whip up a quick game&lt;/a&gt; for the event. This was the inspiration I needed to start getting back in to game development, and I picked up where I left off on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.beccalia.com&quot;&gt;Beccalia&lt;/a&gt; series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, where I left off was still the planning stages. I’ve made some solid progress, but my goodness is it mentally draining. I know that having everything properly laid out is going to make the actual dev process much smoother (and result in a better product overall), but it’s definitely quite tedious at times. With any luck, I can get the planning completed this weekend and be ready to start building.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Community News&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some big community news this week - I found out I was selected to participate in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eddiehub.org/&quot;&gt;EddieHub Ambassador programme&lt;/a&gt;. For those who do not know, EddieHub is a community of developers focused on creating a safe and inclusive space to collaborate on open source work. If you are interested in open source, regardless of where you are at in your journey, this community will have a place for you. I am excited to see what this partnership brings, and as a member of the initial selection wave, eager to help shape the programme for future Ambassadors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other community news, I overhaulled my own &lt;a href=&quot;https://chat.nhcarrigan.com&quot;&gt;discord server&lt;/a&gt; - I found that many new members were unsure of the purpose of the community, so I attempted a bit of a restructuring to help guide folks to a better understanding. So far, it seems to have been effective, and we are nearly at the 500 member mark (a milestone which will unlock better levels of analytics for the server).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Other Stuff&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Work continues to go well. My role at &lt;a href=&quot;https://freecodecamp.org&quot;&gt;freeCodeCamp&lt;/a&gt; is as enjoyable as it was when I first started. I’m in the process of negotiating some part time work with another client, which would significantly help my financial goals. I’m also settling in well to my community management roles with &lt;a href=&quot;https://streamcord.io&quot;&gt;Streamcord&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://tweetshift.com&quot;&gt;TweetShift&lt;/a&gt;. Assuming this additional client pans out, I’ll probably be at my limit for the amount of work I can take on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been on an art kick lately, ordering commissions of myself - there’s something satisfying about the dopamine kick from receiving new art, and my gallery page is starting to fill out nicely. I’d order more, but I do need to mind the budget on that. Maybe another round of commissions next month. Would you like to &lt;a href=&quot;https://donate.nhcarrigan.com&quot;&gt;sponsor one&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think that covers everything I have to share for the week. Thanks for reading, and we’ll see you next time!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Welcome to my Blog!]]></title><description><![CDATA[Hey there! Welcome to my blog! I go back and forth a lot on whether or not I want a blog, so it’s entirely possible that this ends up…]]></description><link>https://blog.nhcarrigan.com/welcome/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.nhcarrigan.com/welcome/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Hey there! Welcome to my blog! I go back and forth a lot on whether or not I want a blog, so it’s entirely possible that this ends up getting deleted… But for now, here it is!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My goal with this blog is to post an update every weekend with general thoughts about how my week went. These thoughts will be some dev-related stuff, but probably mostly personal stuff. Honestly not sure yet - we’ll see how this unfolds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, for more real time updates (and more permanent sources), take a look at my socials below!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Socials&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best place to get real time updates is definitely my &lt;a href=&quot;https://chat.nhcarrigan.com&quot;&gt;Discord server&lt;/a&gt; - I’ve got all sorts of systems in there to show what I’m working on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/nhcarrigan&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; is also a good place to go, though that’s less development related and more random.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can check out the rest of my socials available on my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nhcarrigan.com&quot;&gt;homepage&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>