<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Naomi's Blog RSS Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[This blog contains Naomi's random ramblings and thoughts.]]></description><link>https://blog.naomi.lgbt</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 15:49:30 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Big Plans for the Future!]]></title><description><![CDATA[I’ve spent quite a bit of time thinking about things this week, and I think I’ve finally determined my 10-year plan. But before I get in to…]]></description><link>https://blog.naomi.lgbt/2022/July/2022-07-09/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.naomi.lgbt/2022/July/2022-07-09/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I’ve spent quite a bit of time thinking about things this week, and I think I’ve finally determined my 10-year plan. But before I get in to that…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Client Work&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My client work continues to go well. I have managed to find the perfect balance for the amount of work I can take on, which is exactly what I was hoping for. As I continue to juggle things, I’ll be able to make some moves toward my long term plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over at freeCodeCamp, things have been moving steadily. I got the rewrite of the first JavaScript project ready for review, and took care of our migration back to Discord. Rythm has been keeping me busy as well, with a whole road map of projects to build - many of which I am very excited about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Sema, I need to find some time to properly outline our current issues and fill them out a bit more. Then I need to generate some engagement with the community and get some contributors involved with these projects. There’s a lot to do, and there hasn’t been as much forward momentum as I’d like. Over at 4C and TweetShift, I really need to start driving some events and community interaction. The challenge here is really determining what kind of events would best fit the community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Personal Stuff&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve managed to eke out some time for a bit of gaming, too. Just a little bit, maybe an hour or so each night to unwind. I picked up a couple of indie games that are similar to Fire Emblem and Final Fantasy Tactics, which is a game play style I really enjoy - it’s something that I can take my time and think about, and not have to worry about giving it 100% of my focus when I’m playing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My personal projects are still quite neglected. I found a bit of time to throw some new features on Becca Lyria, but my Beccalia game development is entirely stagnated. I’m hoping to find a bit more time in my week to refocus on this so I can hit an end-of-year launch goal. This one needs to be done right, though, because I intend to monetise it and see if I can generate some additional revenue streams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Goals Time!!!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is probably the bit you’ve been waiting for. I’ve been spending quite a bit of time thinking about my long-term plans, and talking with people close to me about my overall goals. But it wasn’t until I had a coffee chat with a complete stranger this week and they asked me “What are your goals?” that I really landed on my decision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a freelancer, I technically run my own business. I’m licensed as a sole proprietor, and have to pay business taxes (but also get business perks). The biggest benefit of this is that I have a lot of freedom in how I go forward. Which leads me to my overall plan…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within the next two years, I’d like to have enough capital set aside to incorporate as a proper LLC. This opens up the opportunity to actually hire employees. From there, over the next eight years, the goal would be to balance the revenue and expenses such that I could start hiring additional developers. That’s right - my ten-year plan is to turn what I do into a proper consulting firm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s the kicker. As someone who is actively engaged in communities that are helping folks transition into their first developer role, I am far too aware of just how difficult it is to break in to the industry. It’s hard to get companies to take a chance on you without prior experience. Coding interviews, especially those with DSA questions, are also a huge pain point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I’d want our hiring process to focus specifically on lowering the barrier of entry for new developers. It’s something I am passionate about in the personal work I do, and my company would reflect that value (along with my other values). The challenge, of course, is that breaking into the industry is hard &lt;em&gt;because&lt;/em&gt; there’s so much risk involved with hiring. But I’m confident that, as I get closer to making this a reality, I’ll be able to determine a way to make this work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, I’d strive to take on clients that specifically align with our own values - places like freeCodeCamp and Sema, where the goal is to make development work accessible for everyone, and encourage collaboration in open source. We’d also be able to build our own internal products, such as expanding on Becca Lyria and continuing the Beccalia game series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None of this is going to be easy. Not only will it require a lot of information, knowledge, and work - I’ll likely need to consult with a business lawyer, for example, and an accountant - but it’s also going to take quite a bit of cash to make it happen. But if I can make this happen… if I can create a business that allows me to do the things I love AND help people get their first opportunity, then it will all be worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in supporting or getting involved with this vision, there’s a couple of things you can do! First, consider joining our &lt;a href=&quot;https://chat.nhcarrigan.com&quot;&gt;Discord community&lt;/a&gt; where you can see the things we are working on and be involved in the discussions. Second, remember that you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://donate.nhcarrigan.com&quot;&gt;sponsor the work we do&lt;/a&gt; which allows us to do more (and reach our long-term goals faster).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a big undertaking, and it may or may not work out as planned. But I am very excited for what our future holds.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Busy Busy Busy]]></title><description><![CDATA[I was so busy that I actually skipped last week’s blog post. Apologies to anyone who actively reads this blog and was looking forward to a…]]></description><link>https://blog.naomi.lgbt/2022/July/2022-07-02/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.naomi.lgbt/2022/July/2022-07-02/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I was so busy that I actually skipped last week’s blog post. Apologies to anyone who actively reads this blog and was looking forward to a post. ):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Client Work&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over at freeCodeCamp, I spent the last two weeks re-writing our first new JavaScript lesson to better fit the curriculum design we followed with the Responsive Web Design section. I think the biggest challenge is that, with a project based design, we have to teach DOM manipulation right out of the gate. I worry that it might be overwhelming for new developers to be learning that at the same time as they’re learning the fundamentals of JavaScript. I suppose we’ll see how it goes when we release the beta!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rythm has a whole pipeline of projects lined up for me. I’m excited to build all of them, but it is so much to do. Loving what I build does make things easier, but there’s not much time for other hobbies - my own personal projects, for example, are going quite neglected. Things with Sema are also going quite well. Our first open source projects are starting to gain traction, and our community continues to grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Personal Stuff&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried getting back in to Star Wars: The Old Republic - it was loads of fun! But I really don’t have the free time available to justify paying for a subscription-based MMO. I ended up uninstalling it yesterday and downloaded Pathfinder: Wrath of the Righteous instead. The advantage of a single-player game is that I can pick it up when I do have a couple of hours to spare, and not have to worry about long-term time commitments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think that’s really all I’ve got to talk about this week. See you all next time!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Highly Productive!]]></title><description><![CDATA[This week was actually remarkably productive! I shipped two products and they both worked! Client Work I built and launched a new level…]]></description><link>https://blog.naomi.lgbt/2022/June/2022-06-18/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.naomi.lgbt/2022/June/2022-06-18/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;This week was actually remarkably productive! I shipped two products and they both worked!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Client Work&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I built and launched a new level system and membership gating system for Rythm this week. It is absolutely wild that I build bots for a community of 300,000 people, and that they work! I’ve been developing things for two years, and I still can’t wrap my head around the idea that I’m good enough to get paid for it. It’s so mind blowing. People pay me for my code. What???&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over at Sema, we launched the developer rubric Discord bot. I, personally, didn’t write the code for this, but I hope that my support is what helped Vyom build the product. I did, however, manage our first moderator interview today! It went quite well, but is still only an early step in our efforts to build a community. One step at a time, though!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At freeCodeCamp, we moved our translation efforts/discussion over to Discord. This required some extra focus on my end, so that I could help structure the new community direction and get everything ready. It was a nice chance to put my community building skills to work, and I like to think it went well. I suppose time will tell!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I wrote this post (and took a nap), I received another client project (to maybe start on Monday). The work never ends!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Personal Stuff&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been so busy that I really haven’t had any time for personal stuff. I do know I’ve been struggling a bit, but it’s nothing I can’t handle. For now, I think I’ll end this blog post and get some more rest!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[This Was a Good Week!]]></title><description><![CDATA[This week started off a bit slow, but I was able to get out of my funk about halfway through and hit the ground running. I managed to be…]]></description><link>https://blog.naomi.lgbt/2022/June/2022-06-11/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.naomi.lgbt/2022/June/2022-06-11/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;This week started off a bit slow, but I was able to get out of my funk about halfway through and hit the ground running. I managed to be quite productive, delivering a client project and keeping up on my other work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly, I really don’t have much to say this week. I’m just in my corner plugging along. But I told myself I’d at least make some sort of post. So… here it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My Twitter is WAY more entertaining. You should go there.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Another Week Down!]]></title><description><![CDATA[Time is weird. I can’t believe we’re already almost halfway through the year. Where did all the days go? (Probably working, to be honest…]]></description><link>https://blog.naomi.lgbt/2022/June/2022-06-05/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.naomi.lgbt/2022/June/2022-06-05/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Time is weird. I can’t believe we’re already almost halfway through the year. Where did all the days go? (Probably working, to be honest). The days do just seem to fly by, regardless of how productive I am.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I say I’m productive, but I keep getting distracted while writing this. Oops!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Personal News&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had to put one of our cats down this week. It was rough, but I think the hardest part has been seeing how rough it is on the family. In more positive news, though, I started my HRT this week! I’m very excited to see the changes I have wanted for years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also started playing Star Wars: The Old Republic again, in the little free time I have. It’s been long enough since I last played that I’ve got a new account and a new character, and it looks like there is a lot more content now than there was years ago. I’ve been thoroughly enjoying it, though we’ll see if I continue to have enough free time to justify the subscription cost. Because…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Client Work&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I signed the Rythm contract! I’ll be working with them on a part time schedule to build some really cool stuff. Unfortunately, I can’t quite talk about the things I’m building until they’re built, so I don’t have any updates to share yet!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Work at freeCodeCamp continues as well - my current focus is to assist with building the new JavaScript curriculum. We’ll be following the same design pattern as we did with the Responsive Web Design curriculum, and I’m excited to see what we can do with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over at Sema, we’re gearing up to launch a couple of open source projects that I am very excited about. We’ll be building some cool tools to help developers assess their skill levels and get a sense of where to focus their learning. Additionally, I’m eager to work with Vyom and Krish and help mentor and guide them to their own goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Community Stuff&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had the pleasure of speaking on a couple of Twitter spaces this week, and I’m reminded again of how much I love them. It’s great to be able to engage with folks and help them in their journey. And the voice-based interaction is a nice change of pace from my usual Discord interactions, where everything is text based.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our &lt;a href=&quot;https://chat.nhcarrigan.com&quot;&gt;Discord Community&lt;/a&gt; still hovers right around the 500 member mark. Our growth has stagnated a bit, and I’m hoping to re-engage it. I’m just not quite sure how, yet. We’ll get there though!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, thanks for reading! I keep getting distracted, so I think I’ll end it here. See you next week!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Struggle]]></title><description><![CDATA[This week has been pretty tough on my anxiety. I can’t say if it’s because I’m working too much, or because I’m worried about last week’s…]]></description><link>https://blog.naomi.lgbt/2022/May/2022-05-28/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.naomi.lgbt/2022/May/2022-05-28/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;This week has been pretty tough on my anxiety. I can’t say if it’s because I’m working too much, or because I’m worried about last week’s blood draw results, or if it’s something else. But I have definitely been leaning too heavily into my vices this week and I need to fix that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Client Work&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was less productive this week than I’d have liked. I did manage to get work done for freeCodeCamp, but the stuff that would normally take my usual 8 hours took 12 or 14, which left me running behind on everything else. I’m sure I will get caught up with no issue, though I do plan to take this weekend off (it’s a three-day weekend!) to rest and recover. Hopefully that will allow me to get my mindset back where it needs to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My other client work has also fallen behind, and I’ve definitely not been engaged with the various communities as much as I’d like. I’ll catch up next week, I’m sure, but for now I need to take the time off to focus on myself. Thankfully, the work that I do is very flexible and I’m able to rearrange my schedule as needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Other Stuff&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been binge watching Brooklyn Nine Nine. I have my thoughts about the police force here in the US, but I will say that the show has been highly enjoyable. I connect pretty strongly with one of the characters, who frequently enacts off-the-wall and zany plans - I tend to have my own wild ideas, and sometimes think I should act on them more often.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think that’s it for this week’s blog post. I don’t really have much to share this week. I’m just in my corner, trying to survive. I set up a comments thing - we’ll see if anyone ends up using it.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[What a Whirlwind]]></title><description><![CDATA[This week just flew by - there were so many things going on and so many things to share. It was one of those weeks where I signed in on…]]></description><link>https://blog.naomi.lgbt/2022/May/2022-05-21/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.naomi.lgbt/2022/May/2022-05-21/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;This week just flew by - there were so many things going on and so many things to share. It was one of those weeks where I signed in on Monday, looked up, and it was already Friday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Personal Updates&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with the personal news this week. The biggest news is I got my legal name change! Ya girl is officially Naomi. Updating my information everywhere (such as banks and whatnot) was a bit of a pain, and took multiple trips throughout the week. But it feels incredible to have my legal documents reflect who I am.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also had a consultation for HRT! The initial appointment was mostly to confirm this is really what I want - and to order some blood tests. Got the results for those back, and it looks like I’ve got some high cholesterol. I’ll have to get that under control, and quit smoking (which is remarkably hard). My follow up to go over the blood work is not for a couple weeks, but it couldn’t hurt to start making positive changes sooner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My heart has also been acting up this week - I assume it’s the anxiety from everything I have going on. It’s been a very hectic week, after all. I’m hoping that spending some time for myself this weekend will resolve this, but if not I’ll have to address it with my doctor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Client Work&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;freeCodeCamp had a brief outage this week. We were able to resolve it, but it was an all-hands-on-deck type of situation to triage and resolve. I ended up having to fumble my way through some areas of the code base that I never really touch. This definitely made the impostor syndrome hit hard - thankfully I was able to pair with some teammates to work through it together. It’s incredibly helpful to be able to bounce ideas off someone in real time, and something I should probably do more often.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other news, I’m getting closer to that part time contract with Rythm. My work with Sema is off to a very strong start, and we’ve had some great discussions and planning sessions regarding the shape of the community. I’m excited for the direction things are going there. The 4C community has been a bit tougher - the community tends to be active in my off hours, which has made it a bit tricky to get a read on how things flow. I’ll get there, of course, but it’ll take longer than I’d like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Other Projects&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My game development has stalled out again. I’ve been so busy with my other work that any time I might have to spend on game development has been spent on gaming and trying to unwind. I hope to carve out some time to work on it this weekend, but I also don’t want to push myself too hard. I think I’ll play it by ear and see how the weekend goes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Becca Lyria has received a couple of small updates, but nothing major. I’m brainstorming a way to reward folks who vote for the bot and server on top.gg - torn between leveraging the currency system and leveraging roles within our community. I might do a combination of the two. Maybe currency rewards on every vote, and a monthly role award for the top voter? Something to think about for sure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did have a great call with my fellow &lt;a href=&quot;https://eddiehub.org&quot;&gt;EddieHub&lt;/a&gt; ambassadors - we had some very productive conversations about content creation, community building, and some plans for an upcoming Twitter space! Excited to see how that unfolds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My &lt;a href=&quot;https://chat.nhcarrigan.com&quot;&gt;own community&lt;/a&gt; just reached 500 members, which is very exciting. I’m hoping we continue to maintain our steady but healthy growth, and that folks find the community to be a safe space to explore their interests. If you haven’t joined, I encourage you to do so!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And my usual reminder: If you like what I do, &lt;a href=&quot;https://donate.nhcarrigan.com&quot;&gt;sponsor me&lt;/a&gt; so I can continue to do it! Thanks for reading!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Just Keep Coding]]></title><description><![CDATA[This week was another highly productive week. It always feels good to get a bunch of things done, but there were definitely a couple of days…]]></description><link>https://blog.naomi.lgbt/2022/May/2022-05-15/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.naomi.lgbt/2022/May/2022-05-15/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;This week was another highly productive week. It always feels good to get a bunch of things done, but there were definitely a couple of days where I finished a task and then wondered where all my time went.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Client Work&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over at freeCodeCamp, we launched our new Responsive Web Design curriculum out of beta. The roll-out went surprisingly well, and many campers seem to be enjoying the new approach. There was some dissonance, which is to be expected with any change - people seem to be naturally resistant to change. There have been a couple of key pain points that we’re actively working on fixes for, but overall it is going quite smoothly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other news, I’ve taken on a couple of new Community Management roles for 4C (a content-creation community) and for Sema (a startup looking to build tools that facilitate open source and code review). I am excited to see what I can achieve in these roles. Honestly, if I wasn’t a developer, community management would probably be my next career choice. There’s something inherently fun with building spaces where folks can come together around specific interests and have a safe place to discuss those interests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I consider myself incredibly fortunate that I am able to not only pursue my passions, but also turn them into revenue streams. Not many people are able to do this, which is just another reason I firmly believe I am exactly where I need to be in life. I was actually encouraged to apply for a role at Google this week - I politely declined. Despite the appeal of a Google salary, giving up the freedom I have to do what brings me joy and fulfilment is not worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Personal Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve got some exciting personal things going on in the upcoming days. I’m hesitant to share what these are - don’t count your chickens before they hatch, and all. But they’ll definitely be included in next week’s update (and earlier, on my other socials), so keep an eye out! What I will say is that being trans is remarkably expensive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I visited my family yesterday (which is why this post is a day late). This went well. On the way to our destination, we saw a truck transporting a wind turbine blade - this was cool, but ended up leading me down a rabbit hole. We were discussing the relative speed of the blades on a wind turbine, and I did the maths. On average, the relative speed of the blades (at the tip of the blade) is around 466 kph. Also, did you know that the blades have saw teeth on them? This reduces the sound generated in motion by about half.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was fun to dive in to the maths on that, and dust off some skills I haven’t used in a long time. I tend to be easily distracted, so I have a feeling I’ll be diving in to more rabbit holes like that soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Social Stuff&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week I was able to get more engaged with the other communities I’m in. It felt nice to sort of fall back in to a routine - I’m starting to get my various workloads balanced out, so I’m hoping this is maintainable. It’s nice to have spaces where I can help support others as they work toward their goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I picked up Sunset Overdrive, which seems like a silly and humorous game. After a couple hours of playing, I can say that it is quite enjoyable, but the save system seems to have glitches and I find myself relying on the auto-save mechanic to avoid crashing the game. Despite that, it’s still quite enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will say that I find myself feeling guilty when I take time to game. There are so many things I could be working on, and much more productive uses of my time. Breaks are important, I know - but sometimes I feel like I take too many of them. This is especially true when I consider my non-productive social activities as well, such as Dungeons and Dragons. Some things to think about, I suppose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, that’s all I have for this week! See you next time!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Crash and Burn(out)]]></title><description><![CDATA[This week was a highly productive week, right up until Saturday. By the end of the week I was exhausted, and I ended up spending yesterday…]]></description><link>https://blog.naomi.lgbt/2022/May/2022-05-08/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.naomi.lgbt/2022/May/2022-05-08/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;This week was a highly productive week, right up until Saturday. By the end of the week I was exhausted, and I ended up spending yesterday doing nothing but gaming. Taking time to relax is nice, for sure - but I always feel guilty as there’s so much I could (and should) be working on instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Work Work Work&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got a lot done over at freeCodeCamp this week. In fact, it was probably one of my best weeks. I have to say, it feels really good to look back at a successful week and see just how much I got done - it’s a feeling I doubt will ever get old. My other client work has stalled out a bit, as things are on hold while I wait for some stuff from the client.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the personal side, I did manage to make some progress on Beccalia: Origins. Not as much as I would have liked, though hopefully I’ll be able to push forward today (after publishing this post, of course). I had originally hoped to release this game in the summer, but that doesn’t seem feasible any more. Still hard to believe it’s already May! Hopefully I can release it before the year is over, though…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I made zero progress on Becca and Rosalia (the Discord bots) this week. Honestly, Becca’s development road map is pretty community driven at this point - most of her new feature requests and bug fixes come from the communities that use her. Rosalia, on the other hand, is pretty much stagnant. I have some ideas that I could potentially implement, but I’ve got other work that’s currently a higher priority. Maybe someday I’ll circle back to her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Gaming&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of gaming, I picked up Dynasty Warriors 9 Empires and have been loving it to bits. There are many things that the game does well, but the biggest draw is being able to create and play as my own custom officer. Having a character that looks the way I want is essential for the immersion, in my opinion. Those tend to be the games that I enjoy the most.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I think I’m running out of such games. I’ve hit all of the “big name” ones that interest me, and internet searches aren’t turning up any more hidden gems. Most of the solid character creation seems to be in MMOs, which I’m really not a fan of - and to be honest don’t really have the time to sink hours in to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe someone will come by with a cool recommendation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Community Work&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My &lt;a href=&quot;https://chat.nhcarrigan.com&quot;&gt;discord server&lt;/a&gt; continues to hover right around the 480 member mark. Hitting 500 would unlock the full server analytics, so we could better track community engagement. The ultimate goal, of course, is to break 1000 members so we can list ourselves in the Discovery and more people can find us. If you haven’t done so already, you should definitely join! We’re a small but fun community. Hopefully when Discord rolls out the bot discovery feature we’ll generate some additional member growth too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as the other community work, I’ve been somewhat neglectful. Between my client work and my impromptu break, I’ve had less time for communities like EddieHub. Thankfully, things are starting to settle down a bit, and I am optimistic that I’ll be able to ramp up my engagement again. I suppose only time will tell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;This Blog&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am remembering why maintaining a blog is such a struggle for me. It is a challenge to come up with things to write each week. This is very much a personal blog, so it’s really just a matter of sharing what’s going on in my world. But I do tend to be pretty boring, and there’s often not much to share - at least not without feeling like I’m oversharing. I suppose this will encourage me to be more open, at least? We’ll see how long I can keep this up.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[My Third Post and I'm Already Late]]></title><description><![CDATA[Last week was a whirlwind of work. So much so that I forgot to make Saturday’s blog post. So here it is, albeit a few days late… New Website…]]></description><link>https://blog.naomi.lgbt/2022/May/2022-05-03/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.naomi.lgbt/2022/May/2022-05-03/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Last week was a whirlwind of work. So much so that I forgot to make Saturday’s blog post. So here it is, albeit a few days late…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;New Website&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I completely revamped my home page last weekend. While I had been using basic HTML and CSS to minimise the page load and keep things lean, my new vision required the use of Angular to better control the content and flow. What was a page explaining who I am and the work I do is now completely redesigned to feel like an old-school text adventure game. It was a lot of fun to write and design the content, and I’m quite proud of how it turned out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This, of course, ended up inspiring me to get back to working on my &lt;em&gt;actual&lt;/em&gt; game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Game Development&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was able to carve out some time to work on the next instalment of the Beccalia series. I made some solid progress over the weekend, getting the initial introduction scene in place and adding a point for the player to choose which path to follow. I also got the first couple scenes of Becca’s prologue in place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having spent so much time planning out the story and building data tables for all of the game data, I had forgotten just how time consuming actually &lt;em&gt;building&lt;/em&gt; the game was. I’d hoped to ship this game in time for summer, but given that it’s already May I’m not sure how feasible that is. This may end up having to be an end of the year release. But with any luck, this one being a paid game might generate some revenue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Other Work&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m managing to keep up with my client work quite well. Despite being quite busy, I have managed not to fall behind on anything (at least, not the client work). Even managed to ship an MVP for a project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, some of my personal projects are falling a bit by the wayside. Rosalia Nightsong, especially - she was meant to be a discord bot that allowed you to play an RPG game, but that ended up stalling out hard and she’s only got some very basic features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Social Life&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My social life has also been on the back burner. I’ve been less active in a lot of the communities I’m in, focusing on all of the work I have to do instead. I’ve been slow to respond to people who message me. I can only hope folks understand that it’s nothing personal, I’m just focusing on the grind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, that’s all for this post!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Insomnia, Client Work, and a Never-Ending Week]]></title><description><![CDATA[I found this week to be quite a struggle. While I’ve managed to keep moving forward, I have definitely been much lower in energy than I…]]></description><link>https://blog.naomi.lgbt/2022/April/2022-04-23/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.naomi.lgbt/2022/April/2022-04-23/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 23 Apr 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I found this week to be quite a struggle. While I’ve managed to keep moving forward, I have definitely been much lower in energy than I normally am. This has resulted in falling behind on some work, though not enough to be terribly concerning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Insomnia&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest struggle this week was that my insomnia decided to hit me in full force. One might think that more waking hours means more time to work, but in reality it’s absolutely brutal on my productivity. Having to shake the “cobwebs” from my head throughout the day definitely puts a damper on my ability to think about the code I am trying to write. I was thankfully able to get some rest last night, and I am hoping to get everything back on track this weekend, but there is definitely some catching up to be done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Issue Tracker&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last thing I want to do is disappoint my clients, so with the week being somewhat rough the first thing to go on the back burner was my personal projects. I’ve done my best, at the very least, to ensure issues and feature ideas are logged on GitHub, though I’m sure some have slipped through the cracks. However, one pattern I’ve noticed is many people join my community server and ask “How can I contribute?“. I like to think my contributing documentation is quite in-depth, but I believe that having my projects spread across a few GitHub organisations is creating an obstacle for new contributors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To alleviate this, I slapped together a quick &lt;a href=&quot;https://contribute.nhcarrigan.com&quot;&gt;Issue Finder&lt;/a&gt; website. The idea here was to allow new contributors to see all of the open issues across my organisations, and filter by organisation and by key labels (&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;good first issue&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;help wanted&lt;/code&gt;). These key features are (I believe) entirely functional, but the design needs some additional work. My goal was to ship an MVP for this quickly to address the contribution obstacle, which might take some of the pressure off myself for these personal projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;FeedHive&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mentioned last week that I was selected for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/eddiehubcommunity&quot;&gt;EddieHub&lt;/a&gt; Ambassador Programme. One of the perks of that is access to a “Brand”-level account on &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedhive.io/&quot;&gt;FeedHive&lt;/a&gt;, which I have started exploring a bit this week. I’m hoping that the targeted analytics will help me better time my product posts, and being able to manage my multiple accounts is incredibly helpful. I’m sure I will have more to share on this as I settle in to using it and incorporate it more into my workflow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Client and Personal Work&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of my above struggles, I’ve still ended up falling behind on one of my paid projects. I’m hoping to spend this weekend getting caught up and back on track, though unfortunately this is going to set me back a bit on my game development work. I’m pretty much at my limit for the amount of work I can take on - barring unforeseen circumstances (like insomnia), I’m right at the level of manageable but not overwhelming. Now it’s a matter of getting the balance and time management sorted out so I can maximise my productivity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll still continue working on my personal projects, and my ultimate goal is to get my &lt;a href=&quot;https://nhcarrigan.itch.io&quot;&gt;game series&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://donate.nhcarrigan.com&quot;&gt;sponsorship programme&lt;/a&gt; to become stronger revenue streams so I can spend some time on the community aspects as well. If you haven’t already, you should definitely join our &lt;a href=&quot;https://chat.nhcarrigan.com&quot;&gt;Discord server&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Community Updates&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of community stuff… Our server continues to grow slowly but steadily, and we are nearing the 500 member mark. Looking at the metrics, about 430 of these members have been active in the community within the last month. I could probably push for more rapid growth, but I’d much rather have slower growth that results in more long-term engagement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started writing this post this morning while on a Twitter Space (about content creation, funnily enough), which I greatly enjoyed. I still find myself tempted to host my own Twitter Space, to take the next step from speaking on others’ spaces. But I am still struggling to find a good topic to start with - something that I can speak on, but that people would also want to hear about. If you have anything you’d like to hear about, let me know!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In closing, I’d like to mention that I know this post touches on some personal stuff. Honestly, that’s likely going to be the case for many of these posts. As we find success, it is easy to get sucked in to only posting about our wins. In my opinion, it’s equally beneficial for people to see that I am human too, and that I encounter struggles and setbacks just like they do. Developers, especially those starting out, seem to frequently compare their path to someone else’s - if we aren’t real about our journey and the challenges we face, it can be very discouraging to someone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully you enjoyed the read, and we’ll see you next week!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Broken Development Environment]]></title><description><![CDATA[Okay, my first actual post. Here goes nothing… This week was, honestly, a bit of a whirlwind. WSL Issues Monday morning I booted up my…]]></description><link>https://blog.naomi.lgbt/2022/April/2022-04-16/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.naomi.lgbt/2022/April/2022-04-16/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Okay, my first actual post. Here goes nothing… This week was, honestly, a bit of a whirlwind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;WSL Issues&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monday morning I booted up my computer, made my coffee, and sat down to start my workday. Open Microsoft Terminal to launch my WSL environment, and run in to a “cannot find that exe” error. Oh no.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some solid “Google-fu” later and I discover the solution is to unmount the installed distribution, download the update, and use the new image. Which worked - I was back in WSL and ready to code! Unfortunately, my files weren’t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m assuming it was the unmounting process, but somewhere along the way I lost all of the files within the WSL partition. All my installed software, my cloned repositories, &lt;strong&gt;everything&lt;/strong&gt;. I was able to get things back up and running, but that involved reinstalling all of my tooling and re-configuring all of my local &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;.env&lt;/code&gt; files for my projects. It took some time, even with only focusing on the main projects I actively work on. Thankfully I have somewhat &lt;a href=&quot;https://nhcarrigan.com/notes&quot;&gt;extensive notes&lt;/a&gt; for setting up a new environment. Big thank you to past me, who documented all of that for the time I choose to upgrade my machine (not anticipating something like this).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Game Development&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A friend of mine started a game jam in her server, so I decided to &lt;a href=&quot;https://nhcarrigan.itch.io/ruus-goblin-quest&quot;&gt;whip up a quick game&lt;/a&gt; for the event. This was the inspiration I needed to start getting back in to game development, and I picked up where I left off on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.beccalia.com&quot;&gt;Beccalia&lt;/a&gt; series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, where I left off was still the planning stages. I’ve made some solid progress, but my goodness is it mentally draining. I know that having everything properly laid out is going to make the actual development process much smoother (and result in a better product overall), but it’s definitely quite tedious at times. With any luck, I can get the planning completed this weekend and be ready to start building.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Community News&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some big community news this week - I found out I was selected to participate in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eddiehub.org/&quot;&gt;EddieHub Ambassador programme&lt;/a&gt;. For those who do not know, EddieHub is a community of developers focused on creating a safe and inclusive space to collaborate on open source work. If you are interested in open source, regardless of where you are at in your journey, this community will have a place for you. I am excited to see what this partnership brings, and as a member of the initial selection wave, eager to help shape the programme for future Ambassadors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other community news, I overhauled my own &lt;a href=&quot;https://chat.nhcarrigan.com&quot;&gt;discord server&lt;/a&gt; - I found that many new members were unsure of the purpose of the community, so I attempted a bit of a restructuring to help guide folks to a better understanding. So far, it seems to have been effective, and we are nearly at the 500 member mark (a milestone which will unlock better levels of analytics for the server).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Other Stuff&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Work continues to go well. My role at &lt;a href=&quot;https://freecodecamp.org&quot;&gt;freeCodeCamp&lt;/a&gt; is as enjoyable as it was when I first started. I’m in the process of negotiating some part time work with another client, which would significantly help my financial goals. I’m also settling in well to my community management roles with &lt;a href=&quot;https://streamcord.io&quot;&gt;Streamcord&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://tweetshift.com&quot;&gt;TweetShift&lt;/a&gt;. Assuming this additional client pans out, I’ll probably be at my limit for the amount of work I can take on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been on an art kick lately, ordering commissions of myself - there’s something satisfying about the dopamine kick from receiving new art, and my gallery page is starting to fill out nicely. I’d order more, but I do need to mind the budget on that. Maybe another round of commissions next month. Would you like to &lt;a href=&quot;https://donate.nhcarrigan.com&quot;&gt;sponsor one&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think that covers everything I have to share for the week. Thanks for reading, and we’ll see you next time!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Welcome to my Blog!]]></title><description><![CDATA[Hey there! Welcome to my blog! I go back and forth a lot on whether or not I want a blog, so it’s entirely possible that this ends up…]]></description><link>https://blog.naomi.lgbt/welcome/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://blog.naomi.lgbt/welcome/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Hey there! Welcome to my blog! I go back and forth a lot on whether or not I want a blog, so it’s entirely possible that this ends up getting deleted… But for now, here it is!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My goal with this blog is to post an update every weekend with general thoughts about how my week went. These thoughts will be some development related stuff, but probably mostly personal stuff. Honestly not sure yet - we’ll see how this unfolds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, for more real time updates (and more permanent sources), take a look at my socials below!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Socials&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best place to get real time updates is definitely my &lt;a href=&quot;https://chat.nhcarrigan.com&quot;&gt;Discord server&lt;/a&gt; - I’ve got all sorts of systems in there to show what I’m working on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/nhcarrigan&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; is also a good place to go, though that’s less development related and more random.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can check out the rest of my socials available on my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nhcarrigan.com&quot;&gt;homepage&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>